const e={sections:[{header:{text:"Put these sentences in indirect speech"},exercises:[{type:"test",question:'"Will you be free tomorrow?" Mother asked Vanya.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Mother asked Vanya if he will be free the next day.",2:"Mother asked Vanya if he is free tomorrow.",3:"Mother asked Vanya if he would be free the next day."}},{type:"test",question:'My friend said, "Did you like Saint Petersburg?"',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"My friend asked me if I liked Saint Petersburg.",2:"My friend asked me if I did like Saint Petersburg.",3:"My friend asked did I like Saint Petersburg."}},{type:"test",question:'Damir asked, "Have you passed your exam?"',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Damir asked if I had passed my exam.",2:"Damir asked if I have passed my exam.",3:"Damir asked if I passed my exam."}},{type:"test",question:'Maria asked the receptionist, "When can I see the doctor?"',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Maria asked the receptionist when she could see the doctor.",2:"Maria asked the receptionist when can she see the doctor.",3:"Maria asked the receptionist when could she see the doctor."}},{type:"test",question:'She said, "Will you eat it?"',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"She asked me if I would eat it.",2:"She asked me if I ate it.",3:"She asked me if I will eat it."}},{type:"test",question:'He says, "Did you buy that new hat at the supermarket?"',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"He asks if I bought that new hat at the supermarket.",2:"He asks if I buy that new hat at the supermarket.",3:"He asked if I bought that new hat at the supermarket."}},{type:"test",question:'The teacher said to me, "Does your father work at a factory?"',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"My teacher asked me if my father worked at a factory.",2:"My teacher asked me does my father work at a factory.",3:"My teacher asked me if my father works at a factory."}},{type:"test",question:'"Did you go shopping yesterday?" said grandmother to Lena.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Grandmother asked Lena if she went shopping yesterday.",2:"Grandmother asked Lena if she did shopping yesterday.",3:"Grandmother asked Lena if she goes shopping yesterday."}},{type:"test",question:'My sister said to me, "Will you take me to the cinema with you tomorrow?"',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"My sister asked me if I would take her to the cinema with me the next day.",2:"My sister asked me if will I take her to the cinema with me tomorrow.",3:"My sister asked me if I would take her to the cinema with me tomorrow."}},{type:"test",question:'The doctor asked Nick, "Do you wash your face every morning?"',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The doctor asked Nick if he washed his face every morning.",2:"The doctor asked Nick did he wash his face every morning.",3:"The doctor asked Nick if he did wash his face every morning."}},{type:"test",question:'Father said to Nick, "Have you done your homework?"',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Father asked Nick if he had done his homework.",2:"Father asked if Nick had done his homework.",3:"Father asked Nick if he did his homework."}},{type:"test",question:'The man asked, "Are there any more books here?"',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The man asked if there were some more books there.",2:"The man asked if there was a book there.",3:"The man asked there were some more books there."}},{type:"test",question:'"Was he present yesterday?" the teacher asked the class.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The teacher asked the class if he had been present the previous day.",2:"The teacher asked the class if he was present yesterday.",3:"The teacher asked the class if had he been present yesterday."}},{type:"test",question:'"Did you stay at your grandparents?" she said.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"She asked if I had stayed at my grandparents.",2:"She asked did I stayed at my grandparents.",3:"She asked if I stayed at my grandparents."}},{type:"test",question:'"Did you have a date with Damira yesterday?" said Marat.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Marat asked if I had had a date with Damira the previous day.",2:"Marat asked if I had a date with Damira the previous day.",3:"Marat asked if I would have a date with Damira the previous day."}}]}]};export{e as default};
